（キャスター）
超能力テロ組織“爪”が
調味(ちょうみ)文化タワーに踏み込み―
We've received word that Claw,
the esper terrorist organization,
has barricaded itself
in the Seasoning Cultural Tower.
立てこもったとの情報が
入ってきました
It's possible that they might also
be holding Prime Minister Yabe,
豚骨市(とんこつ)で連れ去られた
矢部(やべ)総理大臣も―
who was abducted from
Pork Bone City, prisoner insid—
同建物に監禁されている可能性が…
（テル）
誘拐実行犯はテレポーター
The kidnapper was a teleporter.
He had the ability to instantly travel
wherever he wanted.
空間を飛び越える能力者だった
And, according to the news, he can
also predict people's movements.
（密裏賢治(みつうらけんじ)）
しかも 報道によると
人の動きを先読みできるらしい
Well, that's not really fair.
（槌屋(つちや)）
なんだかズルいね
How can one person have
two overpowered abilities like that?
１人でそんな反則能力を
併せ持つ者がいるのか
Did you end up with a high fever
because of your opponent's ability?
（桜威(さくらい)）
お前に高熱が出たのも
相手の能力か？
No, this is just from the shock of losing.
（テル）
いや これは敗北のショックだ
I also got a fever when I lost to Kageyama-kun
影山(かげやま)君に負けたときも
高熱が出て３日３晩うなされた
and had nightmares for three days and nights.
This guy sounds like bad news.
（星野武史(ほしのたけし)）
相手 ヤバいな
Do you think they have more like him?
（朝日(あさひ) 豪(ごう)）
そんなヤツが
ほかにもいるのかな？
I was always confident
I could take anyone on.
僕は 自信があったんだ
どんなヤツが相手でも！
But now... I don't know what to think.
でも 今は正直 分からない
(Get ready, wake your psyche up, MOB!)
(Get ready, dig your anger up, MOB!)
(Get ready!)
Coming down, could you fill your satisfaction?
You're a MOB. Can't you feel your own frustration?
You're a MOB. What do you want to be?
Wear your overflowing emotions on your sleeve and break it down.
What do you see once you go beyond your limits?
(99.9! 99.9!)
The mysterious percentage.
Cryin' my life, cryin' my psyche,
cryin' my heart in such commonplaces!
Is that your ideal? Is that your mind?
It all begins when it hits 100.
The MOB is alive. The MOB is high.
The MOB is staying frustrated, aren't you?
Is that your ideal? Is that your mind? Right now...
Your life is your own.
(Get ready, wake your psyche up, MOB!)
Mob Psycho
(Get ready, dig your anger up, MOB!)
(Get ready, wake your psyche up, MOB!)
(Get ready!)
Collision
~Power Type~
（島崎(しまざき)）
なぜ首都を少し離れたんですか？
Why did we move away from the capital?
We could've just taken over
the tallest building in Japan.
どうせなら日本一高い建物を
占拠すれば よかったのに
（鈴木(すずき)）
理由は２つある
There are two reasons.
The first reason is the omurice
in the cafeteria here is to die for.
１つは ここの食堂のオムライスが
一級品だからだ
They use four eggs per serving.
１皿で卵を４つ使っている
（芹沢）
うまっ！
The other reason is I'm from this city.
そして もう１つは
私が この町の出身だからだ
I know this city so well,
I can keenly monitor its changes.
よく知った町だからこそ
変化を観察できる
So this place is memorable to you?
（島崎）
やっぱり思い出深いですか？
Maybe your old friends still live here.
当時のご友人も
まだ住んでるんじゃないですかね？
Old friends and memories, huh?
I can't think of any.
（鈴木）
当時の友… 思い出か
特にないな
I actually don't mind if you destroy it all.
なんなら
全て破壊してもかまわない
Really? Even though you
remember the omurice?
（峯岸(みねぎし)）
へえ オムライスは覚えてるのに？
フッ そうだな
Correct.
The special anti-terrorism squad has arrived.
（ＳＡＴ隊員）
テロ対策特殊急襲部隊 現着した
We will now raid the Cultural Tower.
これより文化タワーに突入する
Should I go?
（柴田(しばた)）
俺が行くか？
（鈴木）
その必要はない
There's no need.
“爪”本部の兵隊たちは―
Every soldier from Claw HQ is plenty capable.
１人１人が
それなりの力をつけている
They aren't much inferior to
the upper echelon, the Scars.
支部の幹部“傷”と比べても
劣らないくらいにはな
LP Gas
Most of those guys are
artificial espers, aren't they?
（柴田）
そいつらって
人工超能力者が ほとんどだよな？
When'd they become so strong?
いつの間に
そんなに強くなったんだ？
These guys aren't human...
こいつら 人間じゃねえ
（ＳＡＴ隊員たち）
うわ～！　逃げろ～！
Hey, boss. Just out of curiosity...
（柴田）
なあ ボス ひょっとしてだけどよ
Did you do something to them?
あんたが あいつらに
何かやったのか？
A news helicopter, huh?
（羽鳥(はとり)）
報道ヘリかな？
目障りだなあ　あっち行ってろ
You're a pain. Go away.
（操縦士）
うっ！
操縦が効きません！
The controls aren't working!
（リポーター）
故障か？
A malfunction?!
I'm not sure! It's gone out of control!
（操縦士）
分かりません　勝手に動くんです！
ハハッ 大きいラジコンだな
That's one big RC helicopter!
Leave the fighter jets
and missiles to Hatori.
（鈴木）
戦闘機もミサイルも
羽鳥に任せておけばいい
I'll have Minegishi and Shibata go out
into the town to expand our territory.
峯岸と柴田には
支配域拡大のために町に出てもらう
Serizawa and Shimazaki
will defend this base.
芹沢と島崎は この拠点を守れ
我々の圧倒的な力を
見せつけてやるんだ
We're going to show them
just how powerful we are.
Go!
行け！
（黒崎(くろさき) 麗(れい)）
そんな…
No...
What is this?
何なんだよ これ？
俺たちじゃ どうにもできないよ
We can't do anything about this...
（桜威）
どうする 霊幻(れいげん)？
What are we going to do, Reigen?
Hey! This is no time to be
eating cup noodles!
（誇山(こやま)）
おいおい！
カップ麺 食ってる場合かよ！
Don't act like this ain't
none of your business!
当事者意識が低いんじゃないか？
What are you talking about?
Of course it's not.
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
なに言ってんだ
当事者じゃないだろ？
Huh?
We're not superheroes, and this is dangerous.
（霊幻）
俺たちは
ヒーローってわけでもないし―
危険だ
It's best that we leave this
to the police and JSDF.
警察や自衛隊に任せたほうが
賢明だ
What? Are you chickening out?
（無飼(むかい)）
なんだよ おじけづいたの？
What do you think we can even do
against people like that?
（霊幻）
あんなのを相手に
俺たちに何ができるってんだ？
Well...
（無飼）
それは…
We all gathered here to
ask you that, you dumbass.
それをお前に聞くために
俺たちは集まったんだろうが！
Then, here's my answer...
（霊幻）
じゃあ 俺の回答は これだ
Meeting's over.
解散！
I thought we might have a chance with Mob,
（霊幻）
モブがいればとも思ったが
危なすぎる
but this is just too dangerous.
We'll have to lie low until things blow over.
沈静化するまで
身を潜めるしかない
Reigen-san...
（テル）
霊幻さん…
でも それが正しい判断かも
I think that's the right decision.
I'm going. I'd rather make the first move
than be on the run forever.
（槌屋）
私は行くよ
逃げ続けるくらいなら
こっちから仕掛けてやるさ
I'm going, too!
（無飼）僕も行く！
（誇山）俺もだ！
Same!
This battle is our chance to
find a purpose for ourselves.
（邑機(むらき)）
この戦いは 自分の存在価値を
見いだすチャンスなんです
Do whatever you want.
好きにしろ
Hello? Oh, you're calling
about the fire insurance...
（霊幻）
もしもし？　ああ～ 火災保険の…
Yes, that's right...
はい　はい そうですね
Huh? If you can't figure out the cause,
there won't be any payout?
え？　出火原因が特定できないと
保険金が支払われない？
You couldn't find any kerosene or gas?
灯油やガスの痕跡がない？
Of course not! It was caused by
psychic powers! Psychic powers!
当たり前でしょう！
超能力ですよ 超能力！
You've never dealt with anything like this?
That's not my problem!
こんなの初めてだ？
知りませんよ！
Hey, wait a sec...
え？　ちょっと待ってくださいよ
My office burned to the ground!
I'm penniless!
事務所が燃えて
一文無しなんですよ
何のために保険に…
Why the hell do I even have insurance, then?
What the hell are you talking about?
何の話をしてるんだ？
Hang on.
待て！　見ろ
かつてない深刻な表情だ
Look at his face.
I've never seen him so serious before.
You guys are determined to fight, aren't you?
お前ら もう戦う意志は
固いんだよな？
I've changed my mind.
気が変わった
I'll command you all, just like you wanted!
要望どおり
俺が司令塔になってやる！
We're gonna win!
勝つぞ！
And I'm gonna drag the damn arsonist
to the insurance company!
そして 放火の実行犯を
保険会社に突き出してやる！
Master Reigen's all fired up!
霊幻先生が やる気に…
Now that that's settled,
time to think up a strategy.
（霊幻）
そうと決まれば 作戦会議だ
周辺地図を人数分コピーしてこい
Get everyone a copy of the local map.
The enemy is apparently jamming
all electronic devices.
電子機器は
現場で使用不能らしいからな
Looks like I was being a bit too negative.
（テル）
僕としたことが
弱気になってしまったな
（ショウ）
フウ…
You're pretty strong.
You probably didn't even need my help.
（影山(かげやま) 律(りつ)）
やるな その強さ
僕は必要なかったんじゃないか？
Ritsu, your latent abilities
far surpass your brother's.
（ショウ）
律 てめえの潜在能力は兄貴以上だ
My abilities? There's no way that's true.
（律）
僕が？
まさか そんなわけないだろ
Life won't be any fun
if you don't tell yourself that.
そう思わないと
人生 つまんねえだろ？
俺だって そうだ
おやじなんかより…
The same goes for me.
I'm more powerful than my dad...
As I figured, you really are
leading the uprising, Sho-kun.
（峯岸）
反乱分子の中心は
やっぱりショウ君か…
Talk about a textbook rebellious phase.
中学生らしい反抗期だね
His aura is really peculiar. Who is that?
（律）
すごく異質な気配がする　何者だ？
One of the Ultimate 5,
the highest echelon of Claw,
“５超(ちょう)”という最高幹部の１人だ
that's Minegishi the plant user.
植物使いの峯岸
Get caught by his plants, and you're finished.
ヤツの植物に捕まったら最後
You get turned into plant food.
締め上げられて
養分にされるってウワサだ
We'd be at a disadvantage if
we fought him in a forest,
（福田(ふくだ)）
森の中で戦えば分が悪いが
but too bad for him,
this is a concrete jungle.
あいにく ここは
コンクリートジャングルです
We'll take care of him.
（東尾(ひがしお)）
私たちで なんとかしましょう
Please go on ahead, leader.
（大月(おおつき)）
リーダーは先へ進んでください
（ショウ）
お前ら…
You guys...
All right, Ritsu! Let's go!
よし！　行くぞ 律！
I have my doubts.
（律）
不安
Hey, look up in the sky!
（構成員）
おい 見ろ！　上だ！
（構成員たち）
おい… 何だ？
What's going on?
Are the government's espers attacking?
（構成員）
政府のエスパーが攻めてきたのか？
撃ち落とせ！
Shoot them down!
None of us are getting in those cars.
（霊幻）
車には誰も乗るな
The first step in our plan is to
mess with the enemy formation.
作戦の第１段階は 敵陣営の攪乱(かくらん)だ
Try to buy us as much time as possible
before they realize it's a decoy.
それがデコイだと気付かれるまで
なるべく時間を稼いで陽動しろ
Um, Teru-san...
Is my telekinesis helping at all?
あの… テルさん
これ 俺の念力も
役に立ってますか？
Yeah.
うん　重い荷物 持ってるときに―
It's like when someone uses their pinky
to help you carry some heavy luggage.
指１本だけ
手伝ってもらってる感じだよ
Can you even call that helping?
（武史）
それって
役に立ってるんですかね？
Damn it... I really can't do this alone!
（テル）
クソ！　さすがに１人はキツいな
Would you like some help, young man?
（男）
手伝おうか 少年？
Who are you?
（テル）
誰だ？
Oh, you decided to show up, too?
（寺蛇(てらだ)）
おう お前も来たのか
My name is Takeuchi.
（嶽内(たけうち)）
私の名は嶽内
奇跡の技“超気功”の使い手である
I am a master of the miraculous
art of super qigong.
You just need to make some cars fly, correct?
車を飛ばせばいいのだろ？
What's happening on the surface
is merely a diversion.
地上は あくまで陽動だ
下水道から―
We're going to infiltrate their main camp
through the sewers and defeat the boss.
本陣に接近し ボスを倒す
（麗）
こっち
This way.
One they lose their leader,
none of them will be a threat individually.
（霊幻）
統率を失えば １人１人は
大した脅威にはならんだろう
（大月）
ふん！
It's not just an ordinary paper fan?
（峯岸）
ただのハリセンじゃない
It's been turned into a device
that amplifies shock waves.
衝撃波を増幅させる装置に
なっているのか
Guys, get behind my shield!
さあ ２人とも この盾の後ろに！
He disassembled and reassembled
the shredded vines and leaves?
（峯岸）
ちぎれたツルや葉を分解して
再構築？
That's an interesting technique.
（峯岸）
面白い技術だね
I can even make a human-like doll from a
fridge as long as it has the right materials.
冷蔵庫の中身さえ充実してれば
人間そっくりの人形だって作れるぜ
大丈夫か？
You all right?
問題ない
I'm fine.
The other one's a rare healing type.
（峯岸）
もう１人は珍しい回復タイプか
They're perfectly balanced in
attack, defense, and support.
攻･守･サポート
しっかり分担している
I guess I should get a little serious.
ならば 少しだけ
本気を見せてやろう
（エクボ）
お前は ここにいていいのか？
Should you really be here?
What the hell am I supposed to do out there?
俺が行って どうするんだよ？
Besides, when Mob wakes up,
それに モブが起きたときに―
状況説明ができる人間が
そばにいたほうが いいだろう？
it'll probably help if he has someone here
to explain the situation to him.
But man, he's really knocked out.
それにしても こいつ
本当にずっと寝たきりだな
He wouldn't be out so long
if he was just tired.
疲れてた程度じゃ
こんなに寝ないぜ
（密裏）
霊幻先生 大変です！
Master Reigen! There's trouble!
Our security system picked up some intruders!
防犯システムが
侵入者を感知しました
（霊幻）
侵入者？
Intruders?!
（霊幻）
“爪”？　どうやって
この場所を突き止めたんだ？
Claw? How'd they find this place?
（密裏）
裏口へ案内します
I'll lead you to the rear exit.
（霊幻）
いや 下手に逃げるのはマズい
隠れるんだ
No, it's no good to run off without a plan.
We have to hide!
There's no doubt about it. They're in there.
（構成員）
間違いない　あの中だ
You guys shaking in your boots in there?
（構成員）
ビビってプルプル震えてんのか？
Get your asses out here!
（構成員）
おら！　出てこいや！
What do you want to do, Reigen?
（エクボ）
どうする 霊幻？
お前に憑依(ひょうい)して 肉弾戦 かますか？
Want me to possess you and brawl with them?
I'll open the door.
（構成員）
開けてやるよ
Stay on your guard.
一応 用心しろよ
You got me. I give up.
（霊幻）
参った　降参するよ
I'm not an esper.
俺は超能力者じゃない
感知できるなら 分かるだろ？
You can tell with your tracing powers, right?
This kid here is an esper, but he
hasn't woken up since last night.
後ろのこいつは超能力者だが
ゆうべから目を覚まさないんだ
Let me take him to the hospital.
病院に連れていかせてくれ
This guy's pretty suspicious.
He might be packing a weapon.
怪しいな
何か武器を持ってるんじゃないか？
Frisk them.
身体検査しろ
I don't have any weapons. I just have
my cellphone and a handkerchief.
武器なんて持ってないですよ
携帯とハンカチ
This guy's got something
in his inside pocket.
内ポケットにも何か持ってるな？
Oh, it's just some cologne.
I work in the service industry.
ああ 香水です　接客業なもんで
It's a great scent. See?
いい香りですよ　ほら
Apparently, it's filled with a curse
that causes extreme drowsiness.
強烈な眠気を誘う呪いが
籠もってるらしい
I confiscated it from four-eyes a while ago.
以前 あの眼鏡から拝借した物(もん)だ
To think it'd actually come in handy here.
こんな形で役に立つとはな
（柴田）
雑魚かと思ったら やるじゃねえか
I thought you were trash,
but you're not so bad.
You'll have to deal with me next.
んじゃ 次は この柴田様が相手だ
He's huge!
（霊幻）
デケえ！
Here we go.
いくぜ
He looked strong,
but thankfully he's also an idiot.
（霊幻）
強そうだったが バカで助かった
Seriously, what's with this
ridiculous luck of yours?
お前の悪運の強さは なんなんだ
You're definitely going
to die a horrible death.
きっと ろくな死に方しねえぞ
Mob Psycho
What a splendid sight.
（鈴木）
すばらしい光景だな
We destroyed all that,
yet I don't feel a bit of remorse.
私たちが壊したんだ
しかし 罪悪感が少しもない
Sacrifices must be made in
the name of world domination.
世界征服に犠牲は付き物だからな
Is that really true?
（芹沢）
そうなのかな？
Why the long face, Serizawa?
（鈴木）
浮かない顔をしてるな 芹沢
Let me give you a word of advice.
お前に１つアドバイスしてやる
Yes, President! I'd love to hear it!
はい 社長！　ぜひ聞きたいです
The secret behind my undying positivity
私が 誰よりも
ポジティブでいられる秘訣(ひけつ)は―
is because I've never once
concerned myself with how others feel.
他人の気持ちに全く配慮せずに
生きてきたからだ
I've lived my life up till now
exactly how I wanted.
私は これまで
思いどおりの人生を歩んできた
Everything will always work out
as long as I can count on myself.
自分１人いれば 全てなんとかなる
I doubt my spirit will break
even if I ever lose all of you.
仮にお前たちを失っても
私が折れることはないだろう
I've decided to take over the world,
so I'll do so, even if it's by myself.
たった１人でも
世界を征服すると決めたら する
Since I have the audacity to say that,
そこまで傲慢になれば
もう世界は既に私の手の中にある
the world is basically already in my hands.
Serizawa, I think very highly
of your potential.
芹沢 私は お前の素質を
高く買っている
You held back on Joseph, didn't you?
ヨシフに手加減しただろう？
You need to obtain a unimpassioned,
audacious positivity.
冷徹で傲慢な前向きさを身に着けろ
Then you can be just like me.
そうすれば
お前も私のようになれる
I see! If I do my best,
I can be a corporate executive, too?
そうか 頑張れば俺も社長に！
Pretty sure his misunderstanding
has gotten even worse...
（島崎）
余計にすれ違っている気がする
まず 会社じゃないんだけど…
First off, this isn't a company.
（エクボ）
居場所が割れちまったよ
どうするんだ？
What now? They found out where we were!
First, we'll grab a taxi—
とりあえず タクシー拾って…
（エクボ）
おい！
Hey!
（霊幻）
あ？　なんだ
眠ったんじゃねえのかよ！
What the hell? Weren't you sleeping?
Looks like I've awakened
thanks to you, dumbass!
てめえのおかげで
覚醒(せい)しちまったよ バカ野郎！
Right. Got it...
I seriously give up this time.
あ～ 分かった
今度はマジで降参します
むしろ 俺たちは…
If anyhting, we're—
You idiot! Run, Reigen!
バカ！　逃げろ 霊幻！
うらあぁぁ！
Mob!
モブ！
Psycho Steroid!
（柴田）
サイコステロイド！
I frequently send psychic signals to
my muscles and continuously adjust—
ふだんから念信号を筋肉に送り
調整しながら筋肉を…
Yeah, sure. Goodnight.
分かったから そのまま寝てろ
ぐお～！
Now he's lost his cool.
理性だけ飛んでった
He's powered up even more!
余計パワーアップ
してんじゃねえかよ！
I'm getting really sick of this,
but I'll lure him out!
うんざりだが 俺が おびき寄せる！
He's not coming? Mob, wake up!
って 来ないのかよ！
モブ 起きろ！
ぐお～！
ふん！
でいっ
I panicked for a second,
but this guy's not an evil spirit.
焦ったが
こいつは別に悪霊じゃねえ
人間だった
He's human!
That means I can break him!
だったら 壊せるぜ！
Okay, I retract that last statement.
This guy's not human.
前言撤回　こいつ 人間じゃねえわ
Shit! This isn't good! Catch him, Reigen!
ヤベえ これ！　受け止めろ 霊幻！
You got it! I once joined
the boys' volleyball team on a trial basis!
おう！
こっちは男子バレー部
仮入部経験者だ
（霊幻）軽く頼む
（靴が脱げる音）
Just take it easy on me!
エクボ！
Dimple!
I-Is Mob's body okay?
モ… モブの体は？
That was close... I think he's okay.
（エクボ）
あっぶねえ　大丈夫そうだ
It's all thanks to his shoe falling off.
靴が すっぽ抜けたおかげだ
But now I'm certain...
だが 今ので確信した
この勝負 100パーセント勝てねえ
I definitely can't win this fight!
あんなデカブツに
捕まってたまるか！
Can't let that giant lug catch me!
（柴田）
ぐわ～！
Uh... Are they going to be okay?
（霊幻）
大丈夫か あれ？
The terrorist organization that has
taken over part of Seasoning City
（キャスター）
調味市内の一部地域を占拠した
テロリスト集団は―
continues to wreak havoc across the city.
なおも破壊活動を継続しており―
Citizens are being ordered to stay inside.
市内住民に異例の警戒令が
出されました
You guys won't believe this!
（犬川(いぬかわ)）
大変です～！
ハア… 見てくださいよ
Look!
Super Ultra Rare
I rolled a super ultra rare!
超ウルトラレア 出ました！
For real?!
（猿田(さるた)）マジっすか？
（雉子林(きじばやし)）スゲえ
Wow!
Inukawa, did you spend more mon—
（暗田(くらた)トメ）
犬川 あんた また課金したの？
Fight on! Fight on! Fight on!
（肉体改造部員たち）
ファイ オ～ ファイ オ～
ファイ オ～
You can't go past here, even on foot.
MPD
（警官）
この先は 歩行者も通行止めだよ
ニュース見てない？
Haven't you seen the news?
What should we do, Captain?
（志村(しむら)）
部長 どうしよう？
Guess we'll just have to change our course.
（郷田武蔵(ごうだむさし)）
コース変えるか
いつも同じ景色じゃ
飽きてくるしな
The same scenery all the time
gets boring anyway.
Body improvement! Fight on! Fight—
（郷田）
肉改～
（部員たち）
ファイ オ～ ファイ…
I knew something was off.
（傷１）
おかしいと思ったんだよ
（傷２）
やはり空の車は おとりだったか
I guess the cars in the sky
were a decoy after all.
Which means there's probably another group.
（傷３）
ってことは
別動隊が ほかにいそうだな
Let's get some information out of them.
（傷４）
とっちめて 情報 聞き出してやる
So many Scars...
（テル）
“傷”が こんなに…
But we have to do this.
でも やるしかない
Hey, you're Terada.
（石原(いしはら)）
お？　お前 寺蛇じゃないか！
You really did betray us, huh?
裏切ったってのは本当だったんだな
You're Ishihara, a Scar from the 4th Division.
第４支部の“傷”石原か
What a rude accusation!
裏切ったとは人聞きが悪いな
I was acting as a spy
and gathering information.
俺はスパイとして
情報を集めてたんだよ
今から こちらの情報を流す
I can give you the information
you need on the enemy.
In return, let me join HQ's operation.
代わりに 俺を本部の作戦に
合流させてくれ
ハッ　寺蛇さん！
Terada-san!
How could you?
なんてことを…
This is a nightmare!
（テル）
最悪！
Did you actually think you had a chance
because there were three of you?
（峯岸）
３対１なら かなうとでも
思ったのか？
Never forget that the Ultimate 5 and
mere mortals are like night and day.
“５超”との能力差は
天と地ほどあることを忘れるな
We're almost there.
If we keep going straight...
（麗）
目的地 近いです
このまま まっすぐ進めば… あっ！
Wait, stop!
ちょっとストップ！
Something doesn't feel right up ahead...
この先 嫌な予感が…
There's something there.
何かがいる
What is it?
（槌屋）何かって？
（麗）来ます！
Here it comes!
Hello, Scars.
（島崎）
こんにちは “傷”の皆さん
I thought you were sewer rats since
you were scuttling around down here.
こんな所で
コソコソ動いてるもんだから―
ドブネズミかと思いましたよ
How unsightly.
見苦しい
Let's end this here.
ここで終わりにしましょう
There's a crowd.
（エクボ）
人混みか
犠牲が多くなっちまうが
紛れて まくしかないか
There's gonna be even more casualties,
but I'll just have to blend in and lose him.
Whoa, that's amazing.
（ツボミ）
うわ～ すっごい
Who is that guy? A pro wrestler?
何 あの人？　プロレスラー？
（男１）うわあああっ！
（男２）押すなよ！
Hey, don't push!
（ミキ）
なんか怖い
He's sorta scary.
（エクボ）
バカな！
No way...
That can't be...
あれは まさか…
It's Tsubomi-chan!
ツボミちゃんじゃねえか！
万が一にも
ツボミちゃんに何かあったら
If something were to happen to Tsubomi-chan,
Shigeo would erase me!
茂夫(しげお)に消される！
I have to stop him!
止めないと！
（エクボ）
バリア フル出力！
Full-power barrier!
オエ！
（エクボ）
え？　あまりの威力に
憑依が解けた？
Huh?
He hit so hard that
my possession came undone?
What the hell?
A home run out of the park?!
場外ホームランかよ！
Wake up, Shigeo! Wake up!
起きてくれ 茂夫！　起きろ！
Why did Kageyama come falling from the sky?
（郷田）
なぜ影山が空から降ってきたんだ？
Maybe someone was trying a long throw.
（隈川(くまかわ)）
誰かが遠投でもしたんですかね？
（志村）
誰だろう あの人は？
I wonder who he is.
Those are some impressive muscles.
（山村(やまむら)）
大した筋肉だ
Were you the one who threw Kageyama?
（郷田）
まさか あなたが
影山を遠投したんですか？
Kageyama is a member of our club.
影山は うちの部員です
Whoever you are, I request
that you take your leave.
どなたかは存じませんが
お引き取り願おう
うぐっ…
ぐおっ
Captain!
部長！
（鬼瓦天牙(おにがわらてんが)）
野郎！　ナメんじゃねえぞ！
You bastard! Who the hell
do you think you are?!
I'll show you how much stronger I've gotten!
鍛えた成果を見せてやらあ！
鬼ラッシュ！
Demon Rush!
Now it's our turn!
（部員たち）
俺たちも いくぞ！
うお～！　ファイ！
Fight!
（鬼瓦）がはっ！
（山村）鬼瓦！
Onigawara!
No way!
（志村）そんな！
（隈川）腕１本で？
With just one arm?!
（部員たち）
ぐわ～！
I don't know what you have against him,
どんな因縁をつけてか知らんが―
but he doesn't deserve to
have you step on his head!
こいつは お前に頭を踏まれる
男ではない
Say, Kageyama...
なあ 影山 お前は…
That's right. You've worked so hard.
そうだ　頑張ってきたんだ
No matter how many times
you've passed out from anemia...
何度 貧血で倒れようとも―
No matter how many times you've stumbled...
足をくじこうとも―
You've always been running right behind us.
後ろについて走っていた
その姿が…
Just seeing you like that...
俺たちに… 勇気を与えてくれる
...gives us courage!
それは こんな程度で
折れるものではない！
That's not going to break
because of something like this!
I won't let you have Kageyama!
お前に影山を渡すわけにはいかん！
ぬお～！
（エクボ）
さすが 茂夫の先輩
That's Shigeo's senior for you.
This guy's ripped!
スゲえパワーだ
Here we go! Unleashed!
いくぜ 解放！
Muscle Usage 100%
ぐわ～！
（エクボ）
ふん！
What the hell are you so surprised about?
なに驚いてんだ？
Muscles built using psychic powers
don't stand a chance
超能力を使って作った筋肉と―
against muscles built by
training diligently every day.
地道にトレーニング量
積んできた筋肉じゃあ―
質が比べ物にならねえだろ！
This guy is way out of your league!
Shigeo was right.
茂夫の正解だった
（郷田）どりゃ～！
（柴田）ぐおっ！
フン！
Captain!
（部員たち）
部長～！
You're so awesome, Captain!
（隈川）
やっぱり部長はスゲえや
Is that what they call an adrenaline rush?!
（佐川(さがわ)）
今のが
火事場のバカ力ってやつですか？
All that training paid off!
トレーニングの成果が出たんだ！
I-I did that?
お… 俺が やったのか？
We need to celebrate your growth!
成長を祝って胴上げだ～！
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
（部員たち）
ワッショイ ワッショイ
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
Shit! That guy's getting up again!
げっ！
あいつ まだ起き上がるぞ！
You can't be serious!
ウソだろ？
What should we do, Captain?!
部長 どうする？
Actually... I haven't been able
to raise my arms for a while...
実は さっきから腕が上がらん
I probably won't be able to do that again.
（エクボ）
もう１度は無理か…
うおぇ！
（鬼瓦）
来るぞ！
Here he comes!
Kageyama!
（郷田）
影山！
Everyone from the club?
（モブ）
部活のみんな？
Oh, whoops.
あっ しまった
寝てたのか 僕は
I guess I was sleeping.
Make sure you don't fall asleep
outdoors again, Kageyama.
外で寝るんじゃないぞ 影山
Sorry about that.
（モブ）
すみません
Dimple, what's going on right now?
（モブ）
エクボ 今 どうなってるの？
We're finally here.
（ショウ）
ようやく たどり着いたぜ
Just you wait, Dad!
待ってろよ おやじ
I spilled a seed and lost sight of it
I'll find it using the color it's dyed in and watch it grow
It immediately returned to the palm of my hand
But it's still too light and too frail to reach for the skies
The world coldly drains away all the heat
The bright sunshine just isn't enough
The memories are closing off what lies ahead
Shake off their warmth and set off into the distance
If I let it wither, it'd be over just like that
But my hope just doesn't fade away
（霊幻）
目を覚ましたモブは
調味文化タワーを目指す
After waking up,
Mob heads for Seasoning Cultural Tower.
But he finds himself up against
Minegishi from the Ultimate 5!
…が その前に立ちはだかったのは
“５超”の峯岸！
Leave the strongest of
the Ultimate 5, Shimazaki, to me!
最強の“５超”島崎は
俺に任せとけ！
次回「モブサイコ100 Ⅱ」
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 II Episode 11:
第11話「指導　感知能力者」
"Guidance ~Psychic Sensor~."
Guidance
~Psychic Sensor~
Option B, the serious course, involves buying
the Blu-rays and the manga volumes.
真面目Ｂコースなら
ブルーレイと単行本